原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 Lynn_宁  Alex  杨一勾  小食人魔  木浅
翻译：Giggles  辰星晓Reginamoon   校对：木浅  某羽
时间轴：念念 烟幕迟迟 Toozii
后期：斯人      总监：木浅
诉 讼 双 雄
第七季   第四集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
而且我儿子也进过监狱
My son was in prisoned too.
上面说你儿子死于心脏病
Says your son died of a heart attack.
他们一定隐瞒了我什么
There's something they're not telling me.
那孩子
That kid?
他不会毫无理由就卷进打架事件
He didn't just up and get in a fight without good reason.
你不知道你在说什么
You don't know what you talking about.
-看守受贿了吗  -他只是死了
- Look, are the guards corrupt? - No! He just died!
我想让迈克放弃这个案子
I need Mike to drop that case.
你是在说  因为你客户在欺压你
You telling me to go back on my word
所以让我出尔反尔吗
because your client's bullying you?
这只是个无偿服务案  完全可以放弃
It's one pro bono. He can drop it.
我给你任务  你就得做
If I give you an assignment, you do it.
自从我来  就一直忍受路易的欺负
Since I got here, I have had to take shit from Louis.
你现在还要求我浪费时间精力
And now you're asking me to waste my time
在这种小事上面
and my ability on something like this.
我们不能让你开创先例
We can't have you setting a precedent
让亚历克斯的客户骑在我们头上作威作福
that Alex's clients can run roughshod all over us.
因为你生气的唯一原因是
The only reason that you're pissed about this
你的新猫友为我取消了和你的午餐
is your new honeysuckle friend canceled lunch on you for me.
我不能任由他们逃脱制裁
I can't let them get away with this
我要把这案子交给那个
without handing it off to the one lawyer I know
在乎这件事并且能办成的律师
who cares enough to see this thing through.
如果我们的律所和本案扯上任何关系
If our firm is associated with that case,
-都会失去一个大客户  -我不办它了
- we lose a huge client. - I'm not working on it.
那就出一份书面声明
Then you're gonna put that in writing
而且要交给亚历克斯的客户
and you're gonna deliver it to Alex's client.
我想问问  瑞秋给你的任务
I was just wondering. Have you redone
你完成了吗
the assignment that Rachel gave you?
还没有  我的事情一大堆
Not yet. I had a ton on my plate.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
但我不提出让你在这儿办
What kind of best man would I be
还算哪门子好伴郎啊
if I didn't offer for you to have it here?
要我说  你不提就真的很不好了
Pretty shitty one, if you ask me.
-恭喜  -谢谢  哈维
- Congratulations. - Thanks, Harvey.
你确定他还没来
You sure he's not in?
我可不想撞见
I hate to walk in on the man
穿三角裤的男人
in his tighty-whities.
我觉得哈维不穿三角裤
I don't think Harvey wears tighty-whities.
天呐  瑞秋
Oh, Jesus Christ, Rachel.
我可不想去想他穿什么
I don't wanna think about what the man wears.
好吧
Well...
你觉得如何
what do you think?
很棒
This is great!
如果你也是奔五十的单身汉
If you're a... Bachelor pushing 50
需要打动女人的话
and you need to impress women.
不不不  你干什么呢
No, no, no, no. What are you doing?
-别翻他的冰箱  -瑞秋
- Don't go in his fridge! - Rachel.
他都给我们钥匙了  相信我
The man gave us his keys. Trust me.
他知道我们会翻他的东西的
He knows we're gonna go through his shit.
那么你就是来看他都吃什么
So basically you came here to look at what he eats
然后说这里不适合办婚礼
and to say that this is a "No" for the wedding.
当然不适合  但是
Of course it's a no. But the fact is...
我们干吗要商量场地
why are we even talking venue at all
你们还没定下日子呢
when you don't even have a date?
我们会找时间商量的
We're gonna get around to that.
那么你
Just like you...
也会找时间宣布喜讯吗
got around to the announcement?
什么
What?
你母亲说她安排了一位摄影师
Your mother said that she arranged for a photographer,
但你取消了  花商也是
but you cancelled. Same with the florist.
-怎么回事  -没什么事
- What's going on? - Nothing is going on.
迈克和我现在都在
Mike and I are both really busy
忙于开启我们的事业
getting our careers off the ground right now.
瑞秋  问题就在这里
Rachel, that's just it.
如果你都没时间打理婚礼
If you can't focus on your wedding,
又怎么能有时间
how are you gonna make time to focus
打理婚姻
on your marriage?
这才是你来的原因  是吧
Now, that's why you came here, isn't it?
给我这样的好建议
To give me sweet advice like that.
还有告诉了不起的哈维・斯佩克特
Well, that, and to tell the mighty Harvey Specter
我试过了他的厕所
I took his toilet bowl for a test drive.
爸爸  不许那么做
Dad...you're not doing that.
你真是
You know how to suck
会扫兴啊
the fun out of everything, don'tcha?
天呐
Oh, my God.
你  斯特芬妮呢
You. Where the hell is Stephanie?
-她不在  -什么意思
- She's not here. - What do you mean,
她不在  我刚挂了一个客户的电话
she's not here? I just got off the phone with a client,
她没有替他们发撤销动议
and she never filed their motion to dismiss.
-我解雇了她  -什么
- That's because I fired her. - You what?!
她是我们最聪明的四年律师
She was the smartest fourth-year we had!
她也抗命  我做出了决定
She was also insubordinate, and I made a decision.
我才不管你做了什么
I don't give a shit what you made.
她正在德尔塔证券的案子上帮我
She was working for me on Delta Securities,
-我需要她回来  -路易
- and I need her back. - Okay, Louis,
我不会请她回来的
I'm not getting her back.
那样其他的律师
What kind of message does that send
-会怎么想  -总比现在
- to the other associates? - Better than the one
别人会想的强  那就是这家律所
we're sending out now which is that this firm
-就是个笑话  -路易  你得冷静下来
- is a Goddamn joke. - Louis, you need to calm down
别让这事往错误的方向发展
right now before this goes in the wrong direction,
因为这跟斯特芬妮无关
'cause this isn't about Stephanie.
而是因为塔拉
This is about Tara and the fact
因为你一直没有去面对她
that you haven't been dealing with her.
这跟塔拉毫无关系
This has nothing to do with Tara.
而是哈维要把律所开垮了
This is about Harvey running this firm into the ground.
他怎么那么做了
And how exactly has he been doing that?
我来给你说说  我气他
Let me run it down for you. I'm pissed at him.
迈克气他  上次我见到你时
Mike's pissed at him. And the last time I saw you,
你也气他  所以与其告诉我
you were pissed at him. So instead of telling me
你不打算把斯特芬妮雇回来
that you're not gonna hire Stephanie back,
你怎么不去告诉万能的主
why don't you go tell the lord God almighty
如果他不小心
that if he is not careful,
他就没有王国可以统治了
he's not gonna have a kingdom to rule over anymore!
-早  -哈维  我忙呢
- Morning. - Harvey, I'm sort of busy,
如果你是来打哈哈的
so if you're here to shoot the shit--
我是来给你这个的
I'm here to give you this.
-这是什么  -我的感谢
- What's this? - It's my way of saying thanks.
-谢什么  -你知道的
- For what? - You know what.
哈维  我放弃诉讼是因为你要求了我
Harvey, I dropped the suit because you asked me to.
你不用回报我什么
You don't have to give me anything in return.
有人教过你什么叫见好就收吗
Has anyone ever taught you how to be gracious?
打开文件
Open the file.
这是个无偿案
This's a pro bono.
我觉得你的一案
I figured you didn't get to complete
没能做完  这样才公平
your one-for-you this time, so it's only fair.
而且  你也不希望我告你
Plus, you didn't want me to sue you
-违背我们的协议  -罗宾如果
- for violating our agreement. - Doesn't look good
告蝙蝠侠违背合约可不好看
to have Robin coming after Batman for breach of contract.
老实说  迈克  我知道那对你很难
Seriously, Mike, I know how hard that was for you,
我不希望你和亚历克斯之间
and I don't want there to be any bad blood
有什么不睦
between you and Alex.
我对亚历克斯没意见  哈维
I don't have a problem with Alex, Harvey.
-真的  -真的
- You sure? - I'm sure.
-真的  -嗯  没事
- Sure? - Good. Yeah.
-真没事  -你走吧
- All good? - You should go.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你做首席运营官做烦了  想我了
You're bored being C.O.O., you miss me,
想回来做我的秘书
and you want back on my desk.
我才不想回去做你的秘书  哈维
I never want back on your desk, Harvey,
而且我是来告诉你
and I'm here to tell you
你作为经营合伙人的蜜月期结束了
that your honeymoon as Managing Partner is over.
这是因为你在会议上
Is this about me not calling a vote
动摇我的威信之后我没要求投票吗
after you undermined me in that meeting?
我就不追究了这句了
I'm gonna let that go
因为你得明白  现在
because you need to understand that right now
-大家都在生你的气  -放松  唐娜
- people are mad at you. - Relax, Donna.
-我解决迈克了  -真好
- I took care of Mike. - Good for you.
-三个解决了一个  -或许你不知道
- You're one for three. - Maybe you didn't know this,
但这足以进入名人堂了
but that's good enough to get you into the Hall of Fame.
知道吗  哈维  与其这么傲慢
You know what, Harvey, instead of being so arrogant,
不如你可以想想怎么让我们所有人都开心
maybe you could figure out a way to keep all of us happy.
-首先就是你的二把手  -什么意思
- Starting with your number two. - What's that supposed to mean?
路易现在简直疯了
It means Louis is out of his mind at the moment.
而你又火上浇油  如果你现在
You poured fuel on the fire, and if you asked me
要我在你俩之间选一个经营合伙人
to choose between the two of you for Managing Partner right now,
我选亚历克斯・威廉姆斯
I'd choose Alex Williams.
-唐娜  -听我说  哈维
- Donna - Listen to me, Harvey.
如果让我做首席运营官
If making me C.O.O.
并不是为了让我开心
wasn't just some bullshit move
哄我的举动
to make me feel good,
你得别再犯浑了
you'll get your head out of your ass,
好好听我说
listen to what I'm telling you,
你要明白  你有麻烦了
and realize you've got a problem.
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal*
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife*
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel*
*所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like*
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind*
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money*
*好了*
*All right*
*退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance*
诉讼双雄
第七季第四集
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie*
哈维
Harvey.
杰西卡
Jessica.
看来退休之后过得不错啊
Retirement suits you.
-我没有退休  -你看起来像退休了
- I'm not retired. - You look retired.
我看起来很轻松  这二者是有区别的
I look relaxed. There's a difference.
怎么了  哈维
Now, what's going on, Harvey?
上一次你如此经常地飞芝加哥
The last time you flew to Chicago this often,
是迈克尔・乔丹还在队里的时候
Michael was still playing.
律所遇到麻烦了
I'm in a situation at the office.
遇到麻烦时  要做的第一件事
Well, the first thing to do when you're in trouble
就是向自己承认让自己陷于这种困境的错误
is admit to yourself what you did to get yourself there.
你觉得我做了什么错事
What do you think I did?
我和迈克做了约定  请他回来
I made a deal with Mike to come back.
我没经过深思熟虑就让唐娜当了合伙人
I made Donna a partner without thinking it through.
我违背路易的意愿雇用了一个人
I hired someone against Louis's wishes.
这一切相互交织在一起
And all those things are colliding with each other
导致"人人都恨哈维"
into a big pile of "People hate Harvey."
至少不是"人人都恨杰西卡"
Well, at least it's not a big pile of "People hate Jessica."
这就是你的建议吗
That's your advice?
不  不是
No. No.
哈维  我的建议是  给那个
Harvey, my advice is to give a big piece of new business
最不依不饶的人一个大任务
to the person least likely to let anything go.
-路易  -十有八九是他
- Louis. - Nine times outta ten.
我不能一夜之间就给他变出件任务
I can't just manufacture that overnight.
哈维  你还记得
Harvey, do you remember that time
我们从赞恩那里挖快步马系统那次吗
we poached Trotter Systems from Zane?
你一定是在逗我
You gotta be shitting me.
那次是预先安排好的交易吗
That was a prearranged deal?
我当时拼了老命去争取快步马
I worked my ass off to get Trotter.
确实
You did.
然后你就完全忘记你当时正因一件现在
And you completely forgot that you were pissed at me
咱们俩早都记不得的芝麻大点的事生我的气了
about some bullshit neither one of us can remember anymore.
-转移注意力  -没错
- Rook to Bishop four. - Exactly.
好了  快看菜单  我饿死了
Now, take a look at your menu, 'cause I'm starving.
你觉得我什么时候才能
When, exactly, do you think
不再为这些事情来找你请教
I'm gonna stop coming to you with these things?
实际上  哈维
The truth is, Harvey,
你根本就不需要再来找我了
you don't need to come to me anymore.
你来找我只是因为你想我了
You just do it 'cause you miss me.
我能找你说两句话吗
Can I talk to you for a second?
可以啊  但我只有几分钟时间
Yeah. But I only have a few minutes.
我要上庭
I have court.
我今早和我爸去了哈维的公寓
I met with my dad at Harvey's apartment this morning.
让我猜猜
Don't tell me.
他说他的宝贝女儿
He said a bachelor pad
绝对不能在一间单身公寓里
is no place for his special little girl
庆祝她的婚礼大日子
to celebrate the biggest day of her life.
迈克  你得承认
Well, Mike, you have to admit
我们放弃在时代广场办的唯一原因
the only reason that we changed it from the Plaza in the first place
就是我们不想引人注目
was because we didn't want the attention.
但既然如今你已经成为了一名合法律师...
But now that you're a legitimate lawyer...
我们就不用担心那一点了
we don't have to worry about that.
瑞秋  你说了算
Rachel, it's okay.
我只想让你开开心心的
I just want you to be happy.
-所以你不生气  -完全不会
- So you're not mad. - Not at all.
棒  因为要定在时代广场
Good. Because now that it is at the Plaza,
所以我打了电话给婚礼团队
I called and made an appointment with the wedding team
预约了看婚礼菜单
for us to go over some menu options.
等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait.
你在我答应到现在的一秒钟间做了预约
You made an appointment in between when I said it was okay a second ago and now?
是啊  你没有看到吗
Yeah, y-you didn't just notice me do that?
-我速度超快的  -你真的超快
- It was crazy fast! - You're fast.
迈克  说真的  谢谢你这么体贴
Mike, seriously, I appreciate you being so understanding.
预约在今晚7点
The appointment is tonight at 7:00.
瑞秋  今晚我的公益诉讼有个会议
Rachel, I have a meeting tonight with my pro bono,
我不能推掉
and I can't put it off.
你一个人去可以吗
Can you do this one without me?
当然可以  但我希望我俩能一起去
Of course I can, but I wanted us to do it together.
瑞秋  听我说
Rachel, listen to me.
我了解你
I know you...right?
你会有上千个问题
You're gonna have a thousand questions.
你会想缩小选择范围
You're gonna want to narrow down the choices.
我保证以后我都会去的
I promise you I will be at every other meeting.
好吧  我会搞定的
Okay. I'll take care of it.
-好的  爱你  -我也爱你
- All right. Love you. - Love you, too.
怎么不穿你的男人装
Why aren't you playing from the men's tees?
假如你来说服我
If you're here to insist
同意让我女儿去你的爱巢里举办婚礼的
that my daughter gets married in that love shack of yours,
那就省省吧
that ship has sailed.
就算她在泰姬陵举办婚礼我也不在乎
Oh, I don't care if she gets married at the Taj Mahal.
我是听从杰西卡的安排来找你的
I'm here to take you up on Jessica's arrangement.
是嘛  什么安排
Yeah. What arrangement was that?
你帮我一个忙
The one where you do me a favor
我回报你一个大忙
and I give you a big one in return.
你以为我拱手让卡特里娜・班尼特
What the hell do you think letting Katrina Bennett and Company
和公司投奔你算什么
walk over to you without a fight was?
我没有要你那样做
I didn't ask you to do that.
我不在乎你有没有要求我
I don't care whether you asked me or not.
这个季度收益不好
It's been a thin quarter,
我也不是什么圣诞老人
and I'm no Goddamn Santa Claus.
-罗伯特  -好了  哈维
- Robert. - Okay, Harvey.
你想要我帮你是吧  那我就帮你个忙
You want a favor? I'll give you one.
与其让我救济你
Instead of you asking me for a handout,
不如自己小心
you should watch your backside,
因为有颗导弹直冲着你来了
because you've got a missile coming straight for you.
布莱顿・古尔德
Bratton Gould.
没错  布莱顿・古尔德
Yes. Bratton Gould.
你觉得在你从他们眼皮子底下
What'd you think they were gonna do
挖走了他们的高级合伙人和招牌客户
when you took their senior partner and marquee client
他们会怎么做
out from under their noses?
我早就知道他们会报复
I knew they'd try to retaliate,
但我没想到会这么快
but I didn't think it would happen this fast.
就是今天了
Well, today's the day.
我告诉你吧
Let me tell you something.
我一点都不喜欢他们
I have no love for them.
所以我会尽全力帮你忙
So I'll do whatever I can to help.
但如我所说  这个季度收益不好
But like I said, it's been a thin quarter.
所以我是不会让你抢走我的客户的
And I'm not letting you get one of my clients.
奥利佛  你在这里干什么
Oliver. What are you doing here?
-我得和你谈谈  -假如是案子的事
- I need to talk to you. - If it's about the case,
我不能和你谈  你清楚的
I can't do that, and you know it.
拜托了  只要一分钟就好
Please, I just need a minute.
奥利佛  我们签了协议的
Oliver, we signed an agreement.
我不能这么做
I can't be doing this.
再说了  我还有别的案子
Not to mention I have other cases.
警卫的证词不符合他们对事件的描述
The guard's testimony doesn't match their version of events,
我还拿不出证据
and I can't prove it.
什么意思
What do you mean?
监狱声称医生就在室内
The prison claims the doctor was on the premises.
狱警却说他们得打电话找他
The guard says they had to call him.
我要求提供监控录像
I asked for surveillance video
看他当时是否在那儿
to see if he was already there.
他们说不方便透露
They said they can't disclose it
因为有违《健康保险携带和责任法》
because it would violate HIPAA rules.
该死  那停车场的监控录像呢
Shit. What about surveillance of the parking lot?
他们说那段录像已经没了
They're saying that footage is gone.
那他们肯定有所隐瞒
Then they're definitely hiding something.
可我拿不出证据
But I can't prove it.
如果拿不到新证据
And if I don't get something,
我就没办法推进此案
I can't move forward with this case.
听着  奥利佛  我说过了
Listen, Oliver, like I said,
我不能讨论此案
I can't discuss this case.
但是我可以告诉你
What but what I can tell you is that
如果你能让人相信你掌握了某些情况
if you can convince someone that you already have something,
这样才能让他们坐下来商量
that's the best way to get them in the room.
我明白了  骗他们说我有医生的考勤卡
I get it--I convince them I have the doctor's time card,
证明他不在那个地方
and he was nowhere near that place,
-他们就会和解  -我说过了
- I can get them to settle. - Like I said,
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
不和你说话真好  迈克
Good not talking to you, Mike.
哈维  我们得谈谈  就现在
Harvey, we need to talk, and it can't wait.
那边走边说  因为布莱顿准备
Then walk with me, because Bratton's getting ready
挖我们的客户  得告诉路易才行
to poach our clients, and Louis needs to know.
他已经知道了
He already knows.
他们在打德尔塔证券的主意
They're making a play for Delta Securities,
-而且绝不仅此  -我猜猜
- and that's not their only move. - Don't tell me.
他们还准备挖我的客户
They're coming after my clients too.
AC科技
AC Technologies.
可是  哈维  他们没想挖人
But, Harvey, they're not trying to poach.
他们准备以专利侵权提起诉讼
They're suing for patent infringement.
该死
Aw, shit!
路易  不管你要怎么留住德尔塔证券
Louis, whatever you're doing to keep Delta Securities,
都先等等  我有话
take a breath. I need you to listen
-要告诉你  -我不想再听你的话了
- to what I have to say. - Oh, I'm done listening to you.
你想把这间律所折腾黄
You wanna manage this firm into the ground,
随便你  但是当你的鬼话
you go right ahead. But when your bullshit
让我快要丢掉最大的客户之一时
puts one of my biggest clients on the block,
就别指望我乖乖听话了
that's when I'm done playing good soldier.
听我说  布莱顿不仅想对付
Listen to me. Bratton's not just coming
我们的客户  他们想分而治之
after our clients--they're trying to divide and conquer.
你当你是谁啊  凯撒大帝吗
What are you, Caesar now?
这里又不是罗马帝国
This isn't the Roman Empire.
我不管是什么  你觉得这是巧合吗
I don't care what it is. You think it's a coincidence
他们让你忙于应付你的客户的同时
they're forcing you to close on one of your clients
而以专利侵权对我的客户提起诉讼
while suing one of mine for patent infringement?
你是说我留不住我的客户吗
You're saying I can't keep my own clients?
路易  他是说你们应该互换客户
Louis, all he's saying is you should switch clients
-发挥你的强项  -我不同意
- and play to your strengths. - Pass!
听着  我明白  你不想哈维帮你
Look, I get it-- you don't want Harvey's help
因为你在生他的气
because you're mad at him.
但你至少可以去找亚历克斯
But the least you can do is to go Alex.
他在布莱顿待过  他了解他们的战术
He came from Bratton. He knows their playbook.
我不需要知道他们的战术
I don't need their playbook.
就是因为他  他们才对我们
And he's the reason they're coming after us
-展开报复的  -好吧  路易
- in the first place. - Okay, Louis,
你看着办吧
you do it your way.
但是你最好做好充足准备
But you better be good and ready,
因为布莱顿对你这个
because Bratton knew enough
一年前就差点丢掉的客户了如指掌
to come after a client you almost lost a year ago
而对我的客户提起诉讼的理由
and to sue mine for something
我都还不清楚
I don't know anything about.
也就是说他们在这里安插了内应
Which means they've got someone inside this place
给他们指了方向
telling them what to do.
路易  我能跟你谈谈吗
Louis, can I talk to you for a second?
不行  因为我正要...
No, you can't, because right at this moment--
我知道  你要去见德尔塔证券的人
I know, you're gonna meet Delta Securities.
哈维已经明确的告诉我
And Harvey already made it clear
你不想让我帮你留住他们
you don't want my help trying to keep them.
-但是有些话...  -没有但是  亚历克斯
- But I have something-- - No buts, Alex.
我不想让你帮我  什么帮助都不要
I don't want your help. I don't want whatever you have,
因为我不信任你
because I don't trust ya.
信任我  你到底什么意思
Trust me? What the hell are you talking about?
说不定  你就是那个把我们的
For all I know, you were the one who gave Bratton
内部消息透露给布莱顿的内奸
the inside information on us in the first place.
好吧  路易  如果你真这么想
You know what, Louis, if you think that,
那你现在何不当场解雇我
then why the hell don't you fire me right now?
如果我能做主  亚历克斯  我会的
If it were up to me, Alex, I would.
法官大人  我不管他们怎么说
Your Honor, I don't care what they say.
我们先于他们提交了专利申请
We filed our patent before they did.
你先到的终点
Well, beating someone off the line
并不意味着你就没有抢跑
doesn't mean that you didn't jump the gun to do it.
我们的损失与日俱增
And our losses are growing by the day.
斯佩克特先生  你将上庭对其进行辩驳
Mr. Specter, you'll have your chance to refute him at trial.
好吧  听着  你想听实话
All right, listen, you want me to be honest?
我感觉最近被冷落了
I haven't felt prioritized lately.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
你07年重组时是谁在帮你
Who was there when you had to restructure in '07?
更别提  我去年刚帮了你大忙
Not to mention, I just saved your ass last year.
那已经过去了  现在我觉得
And that was then. And now I feel like
我都打不通你电话
I can't even get you on the phone anymore.
-法官大人...  -别说了
- Your Honor-- - That's enough.
我认为沃尔什先生提交的证据
I find the evidence Mr. Walsh is presenting
足已向前推进此案
compelling enough to let this go forward.
只有一个问题  法官大人
There's only one problem with that, Your Honor.
我们刚挖走他们一个合伙人和其所有客户
We just took one of their partners, all of his clients.
他们为此很恼火
They're pissed about it,
现在是想实施报复
and now they want some get-back.
你愿意把你手机号给我
You being willing to give me your phone number
并不是重点  路易
isn't the point, Louis.
但它应该是
Well, it should be.
-你是谁  -他是亚历克斯・威廉姆斯
- Who are you? - This is Alex Williams,
我们新晋的高级合伙人
our newest senior partner,
他只是路过  亚历克斯...
and he was just stopping by. Alex--
我不仅是新晋的高级合伙人  蒂姆
I'm not just the newest senior partner, Tim.
我之前是布莱顿・古尔德律所的合伙人
I'm also the partner that Bratton Gould just lost.
法官大人  他们昨天和家公司
Your Honor, they entered into
签署了一个付费豁免合作协议
a fee-waiving partnership agreement yesterday
这家公司今天突然声称
with a company that's suddenly claiming infringement
我们客户侵犯了他们的权益
against one of our clients today.
法官大人  他们客户的确造成了损失
Your Honor, their client caused real damages.
如果是这样  八周后这些损失也会出现
If that's true, those damages will still be there in eight weeks,
也就是说你现在不安的唯一原因
which means the only reason you'd be upset right now
就是你的诉讼没有理由
is if this action is nonsense.
所以你是选择八周时间  还是放弃诉讼
So which is it-- eight weeks or drop the case?
莫瑞里近三年的开支报表
Morelli's expense reports for the last three years.
他比大卫・布莱恩在维加斯的时间都长
The guy spends more time in Vegas than David Blaine.
著名魔术大师
现在你知道了
And now you know.
正如你已经知道的
Just like you already know
不管路易接不接你电话
that Louis kills for you out there
都会帮你把事情搞定
whether he's taking your calls or not.
我明天打电话和你谈收购的事  路易
I'll call you tomorrow about the acquisition, Louis.
谢谢你  蒂姆
Thank you, Tim.
干得漂亮  用合伙人协议对付他们
Nice move, finding out about that partnership agreement.
告诉客户
Nice move telling our client
最后一个季度不收费这招也不错
he's not gonna be billed for last quarter.
没什么能比口袋里的钱更能抚平
Nothing eases the pain of a bullshit lawsuit
狗屁诉讼带来的伤痛了
like cash in your pocket.
说到这个  我已经回来工作三周了
Speaking of which, I've been back at work for three weeks now.
我觉得是时候给我加薪了
Thinking it's time I got a raise.
慢慢来  小老虎
Easy, tiger.
迈克  说正经的
Mike, seriously,
我以为你忙着做你的无偿服务的案子
I thought you were busy with that pro bono.
是这样的  唐娜说你需要我的帮忙
I am. Donna said you needed my help,
所以我就来帮忙了
so...I gave it to you.
谢了  罗宾
Thanks, Robin.
别客气  蝙蝠侠
Ah, you're welcome, Batman.
路易  真的...
Louis, really...
-你没必要如此  -什么  开玩笑吗
- you didn't have to do this. - What, are you kidding?
你在我那么混蛋的对你后你还救了我
You saved me after I was an asshole.
-你也没必要那么做  -我有
- You didn't have to do that. - Yes, I did.
因为我不在乎你做出什么举动
Because I don't care how you acted.
我们现在在同一条船上
We're all in the same boat now.
我想是的
I guess we are.
天  你是真的不爱你的旧律所是吗
Boy, you really...have no love for your old firm, do you?
说实话
If I'm being truthful with you,
只要我在那儿  就永远到不了
I was never gonna get where I wanted to be
我想要的位置
as long as I was there.
-冠名合伙人  -冠名合伙人
- Name partner. - Name partner.
说实话  我考虑过离开皮尔逊・哈德曼
You know, I thought of leaving Pearson Hardman at one point.
胡扯
Bullshit.
不  是真的
No, it's the truth.
猎头什么的一切我都准备好了
I even got a headhunter and everything.
-我还以为你爱那里  -我爱
- I thought you loved it there. - I do.
但这不代表我感受不到不被赏识和忽视
Doesn't mean that I didn't feel unappreciated and overlooked.
很难相信有人能忽视你
I find it hard to believe anyone could overlook you.
有的  我就想...
Well, they did, and I got to thinking...
我可以成为世界上最好的律师...
I can be the best lawyer in the world, and...
也不会改变他们对我的看法
it won't change how they see me.
当冠名合伙人之神降临
Like you must have been out sick or something
决定冠名合伙人的那天
the day the name partner gods came down
你肯定就生病不在
saying who's gonna make it up the God damn mountain.
正是那种感觉
That's exactly right,
结果我那天并没有生病  你也不会
and it turns out I wasn't sick that day, and neither were you.
如果你觉得又被忽视了
And if you ever feel overlooked again,
我希望你能来找我
I would hope that you can come to me
我可以帮你解决
so I can help fix it.
对我意义重大  路易
Means a lot to me, Louis.
不用
Well...
如你所说
like you said...
我们是同一条船上的人了
We're all in the same boat now.
瑞秋  你有空吗  我需要你的帮助
Rachel, do you have a minute? I need your help.
当然有  怎么了
Yeah, of course. What's going on?
我认为斯蒂芬妮・帕特尔
I think Stephanie Patel
可能在帮布莱顿挖我们的客户
may be helping Bratton poach our clients.
什么  斯特芬妮什么时候去布莱顿的
What? Since when is Stephanie at Bratton?
今天早上  说来话长了
Since this morning, and it's a long story,
但是有人把我们的内部消息给了他们
but someone gave them inside information about us,
又鉴于她刚刚去了那里
and given that she just started...
我需要你去那
I need you to go over there,
务必阻止她
and I need you to get her to stop.
我  我怎么阻止
Me? How am I supposed to do that?
就是让她复职都可以
I don't care if it means offering her her job back.
但是无论怎样  必须是在今晚
But whatever it is, it has to happen tonight.
等等  唐娜  你不是认真的吧
Wait, Donna, you can't be serious right now.
这是我们唯一的办法...
It's the only way that we--
唐娜  路易羞辱了她  你解雇了她
Donna, Louis eviscerated her, and you fired her.
她是不可能再回来的
There's no way she's ever coming back here.
不一定
You don't know that.
更不用说我今晚和婚礼策划师
Not to mention the fact that I have a meeting this evening
预约了见面  所以...
with the wedding planner, so-- -
我不管你今晚有什么计划  我们得做点什么
I don't care what you have tonight. We need to do something,
而且现在就得动手
and we need to do it now.
好吧  到底怎么回事
Okay. What's going on?
哈维给了我个机会  瑞秋
Harvey took a chance on me, Rachel.
他冒了天下之大不韪
He went out on a limb,
现在我被提拔到了一个别人认为
and now I have been promoted to a position
我还没准备好的位置
that people think I'm not ready for.
我的话不是那个意思
I didn't mean it when I said that.
我知道  但如果我做的第一件事
I know that. But if one of the first things I did
就给了布莱顿搞垮律所的机会
ends up giving Bratton a roadmap to picking this firm apart,
我永远都不会原谅自己的
I will never forgive myself.
斯蒂芬妮可能会不理你
And Stephanie might not talk to you,
但她一定不会理我的
but I know she won't talk to me.
好
Okay.
我去见她  唐娜
I'll go see her, Donna.
在我回去忙我的案子之前
Anything else you want me to fix for you
还有什么需要我帮你的
before I get back to my case?
-见了路易之后告诉你  -什么意思
- I'll let you know after I see Louis. - What do you mean?
意思是如果他没能阻止布莱顿挖他的客户
I mean if he couldn't stop Bratton from poaching his client,
我们刚刚所做的只会让我们陷入两难
us doing what we just did only gives us a split decision.
但你说路易明确表示不要你的帮助
But you said Louis made it clear he doesn't want your help.
他也许不想要
He may not want it,
但是如果这破事没有处理好
but if that shit's not taken care of,
不管他喜不喜欢  他都得接受帮助
he's getting it whether he likes it or not.
路易  在你再次对我大发雷霆前...
Louis, before you jump down my throat again--
镇定  哈维  我不生你的气了
Relax, Harvey, I'm not upset with you anymore.
实际上  亚历克斯搞定德尔塔证券后
In fact, I even came to an agreement with Alex
我和他甚至达成了共识
after he locked up Delta Securities.
-很好  -你呢
- Good. - What about you?
你的案子需要我帮忙吗
Do you need my help with your lawsuit?
解决了  别告诉他我说过这种话
It's taken care of. Don't tell him I said this,
但是迈克冲进他的电话亭
but Mike jumped inside his phone booth
换上了他的超人装救人了
and put on his Superman outfit.
那很好  所以我想...
Oh, that's great. So I guess...
这意味着你现在就剩一件事要做了
this means there's only one thing left for you to do.
我觉得是我们现在就剩一件事要做了
Well, I'd say there's only one thing left for us to do.
你想让我和你一起去吗
You want me to go with you?
你的名字也在墙上  不是吗
Your name's up on that wall, isn't it?
看来你有自己的办公室了
I see you got your own office.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我知道你觉得在皮尔逊-斯佩克特不受重视
I know that you didn't feel valued at Pearson Specter,
我想为我在这件事上的责任向你道歉
and I wanted to apologize for my part in that.
我还想让你知道
I also just--I wanted you to know
让你被解雇并不是我的本意
that it was never my intention to get you fired.
我希望你不是来这里要雇我回去的
I hope you're not here to offer me my job back.
-如果我说是呢  -我会拒绝
- And what if I said I was? - I'd say I wouldn't take it.
好吧  既然如此
Okay... in that case,
我是来查明
I am here to find out
是不是你将保密信息告诉了你的新公司
if you're giving your new firm privileged information.
让我理一理
Let me get this straight.
你解雇了我
You have...the nerve to fire me
还敢跑到这儿来指责我
and then come here and accuse me
破坏了律师-委托人保密特免权
of breaking attorney-client privilege?
否则你的事务所怎么会知道这么多
How else is your firm getting so much information
关于我们正在进行的案子的事情
on our on-going cases?
你以为只有我对你们事务所心怀怨恨吗
You think I'm the only person with a grudge against your firm?
哈维・斯佩克特早就对这里宣战了
Harvey Specter declared war on this place
当时我还没来这里
long before I got here.
何止是我没给他们信息
And not only am I not giving them information,
他们根本不需要我的帮助  也没让我帮他们
they don't need my help, and they didn't ask for my help.
我们说清楚  斯特芬妮  你以前跟我撒过谎
Just to be clear, Stephanie, you've lied to me before.
打破律师-委托人保密特免权
And breaking attorney-client privilege
会被踢出律师协会的
is a dis-barrable offense,
如果我们找出来这里发生了什么
and if we find out that's what's been happening here--
不  瑞秋  我没对你说谎
No, Rachel, I didn't lie to you.
像你说的  我利用了一个漏洞
Like you said, I used a loophole.
因为我是个好律师  也坚守职业道德
'Cause I'm a good lawyer, and I'm also an ethical lawyer.
如果这家事务所获得了皮尔逊-斯佩克特
So if this firm is getting inside information
的内部信息
from Pearson Specter,
他们也不是从我这里得到的
they're not getting it from me.
迈克  等等
Hey, Mike, wait up.
奥利佛  你在这做什么
Oliver, what are you doing here?
我在等你一起喝啤酒啊
I was just waiting for you so we can grab that beer
我们说好的
like we talked about.
-我们没说要喝...  -跟我走就是了
- Except we didn't talk about grabbing-- - Just walk with me.
见鬼  奥利佛  我说过...
God damn it, Oliver, I told you--
放松  迈克  都结束了  吓唬他们起效了
Mike, relax. It's over. The bluff worked.
起效了是什么意思
What do you mean, it worked?
我拿到了一个赔偿金额  很不错
I got a number, and it's good.
见鬼
Shit.
怎么了
What?
这个金额何止是不错  简直好得离谱
This offer's not just good. It's too good.
你在说什么  你觉得他们不会付钱吗
What're you talking about? You think they're not gonna pay?
我是说  这个金额不只是想让你停手
I mean this isn't the number you give to make someone go away.
而是想让你不得不停手
It's a number you give when you need them to go away.
你是说你觉得还有更多这样的案件
You're saying you think there's more cases like this out there.
我是说  这种举动暗示着背后隐藏了更多东西
I'm saying that when someone acts like this, there's more to find.
也就是说  你要说服雷耶斯先生
Which means you need to convince Mr. Reyes
拒绝赔偿  继续调查
to turn this down and keep looking.
你是认真的吗  迈克
Are you serious, Mike?
这家人从来没见过这么多钱
This is more money than this family's ever seen.
而你要说服他们...
And you convince them--
什么  我要找出其他这种案子吗
What? That I'm gonna find all those other cases?
我已经吓唬他们一次了  迈克
I already bluffed 'em once, Mike.
这案子能办成功的唯一原因
And the only reason we were able to make this case
是我们威胁要针对具体个案发起诉讼
is because we threatened to sue them over a specific guy.
那就去问每一个从那里出来的人
Then knock on the door of everyone that has come out of that place
-找到更多的受害者  -迈克
- and find more guys. - Mike...
如果还有其他受害者
If there are other victims out there,
我很同情他们
I feel for them.
但我代表的是奥斯卡  他在受苦
But I'm representing Oscar. He's suffering.
让他拒绝的话  我会过意不去的
And I don't feel right telling him not to do this.
所以  如果你想这样做
So if you want this done,
你就只能靠自己了
you're gonna have to do it yourself.
瑞秋  请告诉我你让她停手了
Rachel, please tell me that you got her to back off.
不是她干的
It wasn't her.
不是她干的是什么意思  除了她还能有谁
What do you mean, it wasn't her? It had to be her.
唐娜  我尝试了跟她道歉
Donna, I apologized to her.
然后威逼  然后相劝
I threatened her, and I cajoled her.
相信我  真的不是她
Trust me--it wasn't her.
瑞秋  我当时说不在乎你有什么约会
Rachel...look, I didn't mean that stuff
但我心里不是那么想的
that I said before about not caring about your appointment.
-我知道  -那你去成了吗
- I know. - Well, did you make it?
我不想让你白白错过约会
'Cause I'd hate to think you missed it for nothing.
我正要进门赴约呢  别担心
I'm walking in right now. Don't worry.
我正好赶上了
I'm right on time.
非常抱歉
Hi. I'm so sorry.
我是瑞秋・赞恩
Rachel Zane.
我是黛博拉・卡普兰
Deborah Kaplan.
我的助理把时间说错了吗
Did my assistant give you the wrong time?
我安排的时间是七点
Because I had us down for 7:00.
我知道  而现在都快八点了
And it's almost 8:00. I know.
工作上有个急事  需要我立刻处理
I had an emergency at work, and it couldn't wait.
但我想  这次见面时间是两个小时
But my understanding was it's a two-hour appointment.
所以我希望  能说多少算多少吧
So I was just hoping that we could go over as much as possible.
没问题
Of course.
实际上  通常第一个小时只不过是
The truth is, I usually take the first hour
我为客户端一杯香槟
to offer you a glass of champagne
然后互相认识的时间
and try to get to know you anyway.
但现在香槟还是冰的
But the champagne is still cold,
所以我们可以开门见山
and we can just dive right in.
汤米・布拉克斯顿
Tommy Braxton.
你还在为那座
You still double-billing
汉普顿斯的房子做兼职吗
to pay for that house in the Hamptons?
不  我在加班挣房钱
No. I'm working late to pay for it.
韦尔还有一栋房  还有巴黎的公寓
And the one in Vail and the apartment in Paris.
这家也太多了
That's a lotta homes.
听着像种惩罚
Sounds like a man who's compensating.
-你最近怎么样  哈维  -他很好
- So how're you doing, Harvey? - Oh, he's doing great.
因为我们刚刚叫停了你对我们事务所的侵犯
'Cause we just shut down your pathetic assault on our firm.
-真是这样吗  -你说对了  就是这样
- Is that so? - You're Goddamn right, that's so.
那我不妨问一下  你在这里做什么
Then might I ask what exactly are you doing here?
我们是来告诉你  你要是再干这种鬼勾当
We're here to tell you that if you try this shit again,
这种事情要是再发生
the same thing's gonna happen,
我们就不只是守卫自己的事务所了
only next time, we won't just play defense.
我们要发起侵权诉讼  让你们赔
We'll hit you with a tortious interference suit
大约十亿美元
in the neighborhood of a billion dollars.
那你要准备好了
Well, you better get ready,
因为...现在就是下一次
'cause next time... starts right now.
你在开玩笑吧
What, are you kidding?
你们这次已经把东西都亮出来了
You already threw everything you had at us once.
-而且啥用没有  -不是所有东西
- Didn't make a dent. - Not everything.
到了明天早上  我要挖走二十个你的客户
By tomorrow morning, I'll be poaching 20 of your clients,
再起诉二十个他的客户
and I'll be suing another 20 of his.
今天你们在法庭玩的那个小把戏
And that little trick you played in the courtroom today?
-明天就没用了  -汤姆  我明白你想说什么
- It isn't going to work tomorrow. - Tom, you made your point.
你很生气我们带去了亚历克斯
You're pissed off that we brought Alex over,
但你不用...
but this doesn't have to--
我才不在乎亚历克斯・威廉姆斯呢
I don't give two shits about Alex Williams.
律师到处都有
Lawyers grow on Goddamn trees.
我想要回我的客户
I want my clients back,
以及他们带来的
and I want the 30 million in billables
三千万律师费
that come along with them,
而且要你亲手奉上
hand-delivered...by you.
-这不可能  -你觉得呢  哈维
- That's never gonna happen. - What do you think, Harvey?
你觉得这不可能吗
Do you think that's "Never gonna happen"?
我说过  不管你怎么对付我们
Like I said, whatever you throw at us,
我们都会回击的
we'll throw it right the hell back.
你人手不够
With what manpower?
你要是想跟区域小事务所掐架
You wanna pick a fight with a little regional law firm
以显示你有多厉害  请便
to flex your muscles, go ahead.
但我们的规模是你们的五倍
But we're five times your size.
这架是你先挑起的
This is a fight you started.
可你也赢不了
And this is a fight that you cannot win.
把我的客户还给我
So you give me back my clients,
否则你在皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特的一番苦心
or your legacy at Pearson Specter Litt
将由你亲手
is going to be that you were the one
埋葬
that put them in the ground.
让我理一下
Let me get this straight.
这个条件给的钱  比我这辈子看到的钱都多
I got an offer for more money than I'll see my whole life,
结果你却想让我拒了
and you want me to turn it down
就因为你感觉说  发生在克里斯身上的事
based on a feeling that whatever happened to Chris
-也发生在了别人身上  -不是感觉
- happened to other people? - It's not a feeling.
是直觉
It's an instinct
是研究了上百个这样的案子之后的直觉
that comes from working on hundreds of cases like this.
如果你接受了这个条件
And if you take this deal,
那你就永远也拿不到你想要的答案了
you're never gonna get the answers you want.
你永远也不会知道你儿子到底是怎么了
You'll never know what happened to your son.
可我还有一个儿子
And I have another son
两个女儿
and two daughters,
这笔钱  能改变他们的生活
and this changes their lives.
-雷耶斯先生  -你的意思是
- Mr. Reyes-- - Are you telling me
你能证明  他们和我儿子的死有关
that you can prove they had something to do with my son's death?
是的  我相信奥利佛可以找到足够的
Yes. I believe that Oliver can get enough to
不  不要奥利佛
No, not Oliver.
要你来  因为你才是接了我案子的人
You. Because you're the one who took my case,
-可你又退出了  -我跟你说了是因为利益冲突
- and then you backed out. - I told you, there was a conflict.
我不懂那是什么意思
I don't know what that means.
那现在就听我说
Then listen to me right now.
你知道我的父母死于一场车祸
I know that you know my parents died in a car accident.
但你不知道的是在他们死后
But what you don't know is that after they did,
有位律师找到我的奶奶
a lawyer...came to my grandmother
给她开了个条件
and made her an offer.
她接受了  没有上法庭
She took it, instead of going to court.
我告诉你
And I am telling you,
她为此后悔了一辈子
she regretted that for the rest of her life.
奥斯卡  多少钱都抚不平痛苦
Oscar, there's no price that'll make the pain go away.
那什么可以呢
Then what will?
竭尽全力
Doing everything you can
不让别人也感受到这种痛苦
to make sure no one else ever has to feel it too.
至少  这是我用过最好的办法了
At least, that's the closest I've ever gotten.
你觉得拒绝这个条件就能做到
And you think turning this down will do that.
我觉得克里斯已经去了  再也回不来了
I think Chris is gone and we can't ever bring him back,
所以这比钱或正义
which means this is about
来的更重要
more than just money or justice.
是要让那些像他一样的人不再死去
It's about stopping other people like him from dying.
而且我觉得这是能做到的  但...
And I think it can be done, but...
哪怕不行...
even if it can't...
我们也要试一试
we gotta try.
拒绝他们
Tell them no.
-哈维  怎么样了  -听我说
- Harvey, how'd it go? - Listen to me.
我之前觉得这本来不是什么事儿
I didn't think it mattered before,
但有人一直在透内部消息给他们
but they've got someone feeding them inside information.
我要知道这个人是谁
I need to know who it is.
已经着手在查了  哈维
I'm already working on it, Harvey.
很好  这是给你个机会来向大家证明
Good. 'Cause this is your chance to prove to everybody
我升你职是个正确的决定
I made the right decision giving you that promotion.
罗伯特
Robert.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
按我听说的话  你得少谈话
From what I hear, you need to spend less time talking
多照看你的律所才是
and more time looking over your firm.
你也说了要是我需要帮忙  就跟你说一声
And you said if I needed help doing that to let you know.
行  谈吧
All right. Let's have it.
你需要什么
What do you need?
是你之前就跟杰西卡提过的
It's nothing you haven't proposed to Jessica before.
你一定是在逗我  你想合并
You gotta be kidding me. You want to merge?
我不是在说真的合并
I'm not talking about a real merger.
我是说放出话来
I'm talking about putting out word
说市里最好的两家律所
that two of the best firms in the city
要是市里最大的律所之一了
are now one of the biggest firms in the city.
你没有人手跟他斗  对么
You don't have the manpower to fight him, do you?
布莱顿现在是要搞军备竞赛  罗伯特
Bratton's making this an arms race, Robert.
哪怕我没有去打仗的人手
If I don't have the numbers to fight a war,
我也得看着像有那么回事才行
I have to at least make it look like I do.
-现在不行  哈维  -罗伯特  不过唱一出空城计
- I can't do it, Harvey. - Robert, it's a bluff.
可这空城计对我有百害而无一利
A bluff with nothing but downside for me.
并非如此  事成之后
That's not true. When this is over,
布莱顿那边带过来的客户
you can have your pick of the clients
-随你挑  -事成之后
- that came over from Bratton. - When this is over,
就会变成好像是我退出了合并
I'm gonna look like I backed away from a merger,
人家不信任我  更不用说
that I can't be trusted, not to mention
人家会以为我弱到
that I look like I'm so weak
要跟你这样一家举步维艰的律所合并
that I needed to merge with a struggling firm
要以此为起点
like yours to begin with.
-你就是这么看我们的  举步维艰  -哈维
- Is that what you think we are--struggling? - Harvey...
你要我答应这个
you need me to answer that...
就说明你还有比汤米・布莱顿更大的问题
then you've got an even bigger problem than Tommy Bratton.
哈维  拜托告诉我赞恩同意合并了
Harvey, please tell me Zane went for the merger idea.
-他不同意  -该死的  没有帮手我们就死定了
- He didn't. - Damn it! We're gonna drown without any help.
那就找
Then we'll get help.
不然你觉得我们在忙什么
What do you think we've been working on?
我以为你在找泄密的人
I thought you were trying to find the leak.
-本来是的  但找不出  -而且既然赞恩有可能会拒绝
- We were, but we can't. - And since Zane might say no,
我就试探性地接触了几个猎头
I put out some feelers with headhunters
看看能不能招几个初年律师和律师助理
to see about getting some first-years and paralegals.
可问题是  我们每个都至少需要24个人
The problem is, we need a minimum of 2 dozen each
才能撑住工作量  但这一年要
to handle the workload, but it's gonna run us
-花掉我们三百多万  -那就去问你在富达的朋友
- over 3 million a year. - Then we'll get a bridge loan
借个过渡贷款
from your guy at Fidelity.
我们去年扩建42层的时候
We already used that line of credit last year
已经把额度用完了
when we expanded the 42nd floor.
-妈的  -哈维  我们要怎么办
- Shit. - Harvey, what the hell are we gonna do?
-我一点办法都想不到  -我有个办法
- I don't see a way out of this. - I have a way out.
给他们想要的
Give them what they want.
我不会放弃你的客户的  亚历克斯
I'm not giving up your clients, Alex.
与其这么做  还不如放你走人
I do that, I might as well let you go.
那就放我走人  糟蹋了你的苦心经营
Then let me go, because I'm not gonna
这锅我可不背
be responsible for driving you in the ground.
-不  我不会这么做的  -为什么不做
- No, I'm not gonna do that. - Why the hell not?
因为你现在是我们的人了
Because you're one of us now.
我也同意
And I agree.
那我们现在怎么办
Well, what are we gonna do?
你要回去找出
You're gonna go back to finding out
到底是谁在透内部消息给他们
who's feeding them inside information,
你们俩负责搞清楚
and you two are gonna figure out
他们会先对哪个客户下手
who they're coming after first.
我要想一想怎么才能打赢这个混蛋
And I'm gonna figure out how to beat this son of a bitch.
迈克  怎么样
Mike, hey. How'd it go?
-他拒绝了  -感谢上帝
- He turned the offer down. - Thank God.
我以为你会失望的
I thought you'd be disappointed.
那是在我找到这个...
That was before I found this...
和这个...
and this...
还有这个之前
and this.
-天哪  -你说对了
- Holy shit. - You were right.
我一顺着正确方向  着手调查
As soon as I started looking in the right places,
好多信息就都扑面而来
all the apples started falling from the tree.
至少有二十名囚犯投诉
There's gotta be at least 20 complaints
未能在预定日期顺利出狱
of prisoners being denied their release date.
而且他们每个人都受伤了
And every one of them involves injuries
还被指有一些含混不清的违纪行为
and some kind of vague disciplinary action.
我的天  他们不仅仅在医疗服务上省了钱
Jesus. They're not just cheaping out on medical care.
甚至在创造收益
They're manufacturing revenue.
奥利佛  这...
Oliver, this...
这难以置信  你找到了集体诉讼
This is unbelievable. You got a class now.
不过有个问题
There's only one problem.
我没这么多资源来独自搞定
I don't have the resources to handle this alone.
奥利佛  我们说过这个的
Oliver, we've been over this.
我签过协议  答应不能插手
I signed an agreement that said I wouldn't touch it.
-我不能违约  -我的天  迈克
- I can't cross that line. - Jesus Christ, Mike.
你是在告诉我  对你来说
You're telling me you care more about some
你签的一张纸比那些人的生命还重要吗
piece of paper you signed than about these men's lives?
不  但我确实签了协议
No, I don't, but I signed it.
也就是说如果我插手此事  被他们发现
Which means if I get involved and they find out,
案子会被叫停  奥斯卡将一无所得
the case gets tossed, and Oscar gets nothing.
你过去做冒牌律师这么多年  现在却告诉我
You lived a lie for years. You're telling me
你连做一个小案子的秘密都藏不住吗
you can't keep a secret about working one Goddamn case?
我向哈维保证过
I gave Harvey my word.
那我该怎么做
So what the hell am I supposed to do?
你应该说服纳森
You're supposed to convince Nathan
给你更多资源完成此事
to give you the resources to pursue this.
如果我没做到  就得去告诉奥斯卡
And when I can't and I have to go back and tell Oscar
这案子无法继续...
that we can't move forward with this...
而那是你的责任
that's gonna be on you.
我知道怎么搞定布莱顿
I know how to take down Bratton.
亚历克斯  我们说过这个了
Alex, we've been over this.
我不会放弃你或你的客户
I am not giving up you or your clients.
我不是想说这个  我手上有他的把柄
I'm not talking about that. I got something on him.
为什么我第一次听说这个
Why is this the first I'm hearing about this?
你知道原因
You know why.
因为不管什么把柄
Because whatever it is,
都是你和他共同的把柄
he's got the same damn thing on you.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
你早就该告诉我
You should have told me this before.
我不能  否则你绝不会雇我
I couldn't. You never would've hired me.
我是说  在他们开始找我们麻烦时
I meant when they started coming after us.
我还希望不会用上这个
I was hoping I wouldn't have to use it.
现在我用得上了  是什么把柄
Well, now I do. What is it?
-我不能告诉你  -你在开玩笑吗
- I can't tell you. - Are you kidding me?
只要我没告诉你  你就算不上同伙
As long as I don't tell you, you're not party to it.
我不能让你牵涉进来
I'm not gonna expose you like that.
我要独自处理此事
I'm gonna take care of this myself.
如果你想这么办
If you're gonna do that,
为什么还要来找我
then why are you even coming to me?
因为你把我带进律所  成为律所的一员
Because you took me in. I'm a part of this firm now,
如果我这样做  我不确定会发生什么事
and if I do this, I'm not sure what's gonna come of it.
这样可不够  你想过去解决此事
That's not good enough. You go over there and do this,
就最好给我保证能办好
you sure as hell better make it work.
好  我们明天就搞定
All right, good. We'll wrap this up tomorrow.
谢谢
Thanks.
我还在想  你什么时候会爬回来
I was wondering when you'd come crawling back.
我回来了  但是走回来的
I'm back, but I'm not crawling.
我来告诉你
I'm here to tell you
你在针对我的律所
you're backing the hell off my firm.
我知道你来干嘛  但让我问问你
I know what you're here to do, but let me ask you this.
你的律所知道你做过什么吗
Does your firm know what it is that you did?
不  但如果你抓着这事不放
No. But if you don't let this shit go,
我不会只告诉他们  也不会只说
they're not gonna be the only ones I tell.
自己做了什么  还会说你做了什么
And not just what I did. What you did.
我要是放手此事
I let this shit go,
肯定会被反咬一口
and it comes back and hits you in the ass.
你得签下协议
You're gonna sign something
声明我与此事无关
saying I had nothing to do with this.
我已经签好了
I already did.
我还给你准备了一份协议
Just like I also prepared something for you to sign
让你保证在未来十年  不会盯着
saying you won't so much as look at any of our clients
我们的任何客户
for the next ten years.
-你愿意这样做  -我说了
- You're willing to do this. - Like I said.
我已经签了
I already did it.
现在这都是你的担子了
It's on you now.
是的
Yes. It is.
搞定了吗
Is it done?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我觉得你很可能到了那里
I think you probably went in there
大概会说  "你得撤诉
and said something like, "You're gonna drop these lawsuits
而且别想追着我们的客户不放
And you're gonna forget about coming after any of our clients."
然后他说  "你们的客户
And he said, "Our clients?
你的意思是我的客户吧"
Don't you mean my clients?"
然后我说  "不  混蛋
And I said, "No,
就是我们的客户"
motherfu--er, I don't.
因为我现在就职皮尔逊-斯佩克特律所
Because I'm at Pearson Specter now,
他不能抢我的客户
and he's not getting my clients.
你比他强太多了  亚历克斯
You're twice the man he is, Alex.
-什么意思  -我意思是  如果船在下沉
- What do you mean? - I mean if the ship were sinking,
汤米・布莱顿会把他最好的朋友
Tommy Bratton would throw his best friend
扔到水里  好让船撑到靠岸
overboard to get himself to shore.
而你  会给朋友一艘救生艇
You, on the other hand, would offer him a life raft.
谢谢  哈维
Thanks, Harvey.
不  亚历克斯  谢谢你才是
No, Alex. Thank you.
我们要怎么告诉路易和唐娜
What are we gonna tell Louis and Donna
这事如何解决的
about how this all went away?
就告诉他们  我们想尽了一切办法
We're gonna tell them we did whatever it took.
而且我郑重道歉  路易说对了
And for the record, Louis is right.
你现在和我们是一边的
You are one of us now.
别告诉路易  我承认他是对的
Don't tell Louis I said he was right.
别担心  反正你说的每三件事里
Don't worry about it. I only listen to
我只会听进去一件
every third thing you say anyway.
我才想起没问过你
I just realized I never
你在广场饭店的会面怎么样了
asked how the meeting at the Plaza went.
我取消了
I canceled it.
-我不懂  -我去晚了
- I don't understand. - I got there late,
然后那个女人还是开始让我做各种选择
and the woman started showing me options anyway.
但我意识到...
But I realized...
我更多时间是在想
I was spending more time thinking about
谁在向布莱顿透露内部信息
who was feeding Bratton Gould inside information
而不是在想
than I was about
婚礼的餐巾纸应该是什么颜色
what color our napkins were going to be.
所以你不想在广场饭店举行婚礼了吗
So you don't wanna have it at the Plaza anymore?
不  我不是想说这个
No, that's not it.
迈克  我们之间出了什么问题
Mike, what's wrong with us?
甚至连一个约会都抽不出时间
We can't even find the time to keep one appointment.
瑞秋  别这样  我们现在太多公事缠身
Rachel, come on, our schedules are crazy right now.
他对我说那些话前  我也是这么跟他说的
And that's exactly what I told my dad when he brought it up.
他说了什么
Brought what up?
他说  如果我们现在都没时间打理这些
He said that if we can't make time for each other right now,
哪有时间来打理婚姻
how are we gonna make time for our marriage?
你是我生命中最重要的人
You are the most important thing in my life.
如果你现在想放下一切
If you wanna drop everything right now
计划婚礼  蜜月
and plan the wedding and the honeymoon
开始选孩子的名字
and start picking out baby names,
那我们就这么做
then that's what we'll do.
问题就在这儿
That's the thing.
我不想放下一切
I don't wanna drop everything right now.
我想结婚
I wanna get married...
但我也很在乎我的工作
but I also really care about what I do.
也许你父亲是对的
Maybe your father's right.
-迈克  -不  我是说
- Mike-- - No, I mean that he's right
他说我们现在自己策划这些太困难
about how hard it is for us to throw ourselves
确实是对的  但是...
into our wedding right now, but...
但他认为我们永远没时间是错的
he's wrong if he thinks we never will.
-什么意思  -意思是
- What does that mean? - That means
我也在乎我的工作
that I care about what I do too.
现在我还得去解决一件
And right now I gotta go take care of something
我早该解决的事  但是...
that I should have taken care of before, but...
等我们回了家
when we get home,
我们开一瓶红酒
we're gonna crack open a bottle of wine,
我们彻夜长谈
and we're gonna talk all night
讨论我们想要什么样的婚礼
about the kind of wedding we wanna have.
然后我们选一个好日子
And then we are gonna pick a date.
真的吗
Really?
真的
Really.
哈维  我知道你来是...
Harvey, I know you're coming in here to--
唐娜  镇定  我来是告诉你
Donna, relax. I came over here to tell you
结束了
that it's over.
你回家好好休息吧
Why don't you go home and get some rest?
我知道你一直加班加点在办这件事
I know you've been working around the clock on this thing.
对不起  哈维
I'm sorry, Harvey.
-什么意思  -你给我升了职
- What do you mean? - You promoted me.
你相信了我
You had faith in me,
我却没查出来这个人  我让你失望了
and I never found out who it was--I let you down.
唐娜  十二年来你从未让我失望
Donna, you haven't let me down in 12 years,
现在也没有
and you didn't start now.
再说  不管是谁...
Besides, whoever it was...
现在都不重要了
doesn't matter anymore.
你好
Hello?
是你  对吗
It was you, wasn't it?
什么是我
What was me?
别糊弄我  杰西卡
Don't bullshit me, Jessica.
你给汤米・布莱顿去了电话
You called Tommy Bratton
告诉了他怎么坑我和路易
and gave him the roadmap to me and Louis,
我想知道原因
and I wanna know why.
如果你已经知道是我
If you figured that out,
-那你也知道原因了  -我要听你说
- then you already know why. - I want an answer.
你来找我帮忙  说你的王国要分崩离析
You came to me saying that your house was divided.
不管你愿不愿意承认  哈维
And whether you like hearing it or not, Harvey,
没什么比外界的攻击更能让内部团结
nothing unites a divided house like an attack from the outside.
这也不代表你就该去找他来攻击我们
That doesn't mean you pick up the phone and call him.
不是我找的他  是他联系的我
I didn't call him. He called me.
他本来就想攻击你们了  哈维
He was coming anyway, Harvey.
我只是告诉了他
All I did was mention that...
我不喜欢我离开时
I didn't like the way I was treated
你们对我的态度
on my way out the door,
如果他想整你
and if he wanted to get to you,
就该挑拨你和路易的关系
he should play you against Louis.
杰西卡  我找你寻求帮助
Jessica, I called you for advice,
不是让你在幕布后面
not so that you'd go behind the scenes
-把我们当木偶玩弄  -哈维
- and manipulate things. - Harvey.
-你说我已经准备好了  -你是准备好了
- You said I was ready. - You are.
而且现在大家也都知道了
And now they know you are,
下一次遇到危机他们就会支持你
and they're behind you for the next time.
-我想我该谢谢你  -不客气  哈维
- I guess I should thank you. - You're welcome, Harvey.
但如果你再干这种事
But you pull something like this again...
我也不需要再这样
I won't have to.
晚安  杰西卡
Good night, Jessica.
晚安  哈维
Good night, Harvey.
-瞧瞧谁来电话了  -你在干什么
- Well, look who it is. - What are you doing?
为明天的庭审做准备
Just getting ready for trial tomorrow.
停不下来的  对吧
It never stops, does it?
-什么  -律师的工作
- What's that? - The work of being a lawyer.
但这也不代表你就腾不出时间
Doesn't mean you can't make time for...
干更重要的事
the more important things.
说起更重要的事
Speaking of the more important things--
我和时代广场的婚礼策划师预约了时间
I set a meeting with the planner at the Plaza.
婚礼一定会很完美
It's gonna be wonderful.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不需要感谢我  瑞秋
Aw, you don't have to thank me, Rachel.
我只希望你能得到你想要的婚礼
All I want is for your wedding to be exactly what you want.
而我想要休息一段时间
And what I want is gonna take some time,
因为爸爸  你是对的
because, Dad, you were right.
我想  享受其中
I want to...enjoy it
为它腾出时间
and make time for it.
所以迈克和我会定下婚期
So Mike and I are gonna set a date,
但不是最近
but it's not gonna be for a while.
在什么时候不重要
Well, it doesn't matter when it is.
只要你开心
As long as you're happy.
很好  因为我还有件事跟你说
Good. Because there's something else I wanted to say.
我听说你和我们之间的虚假合并的
I heard this idea of a fake merger
-计划取消了  -让我猜猜
- between us was floated. - Let me guess.
你觉得我应该帮助哈维
You think I should have helped Harvey out.
不是  我是想说虽然是假的
No. What I was gonna say was even though it was fake,
但我还是为能和父亲一起工作激动了一下
I got kind of excited about the thought of working with my dad.
我从来没想到能听到你说这句话
I never thought I'd ever hear you say that.
卡特里娜跟我说你曾经说了
Well, Katrina told me that you said something once
我以为你绝对不会说的话
that I was afraid I'd never hear, and...
它对我意义重大
It meant everything to me.
什么话
And what's that?
你说觉得我是个很棒的律师
That you think I'm a great lawyer.
而且你为我骄傲
And that you're proud of me.
瑞秋
Rachel...
也许我是不常说出来
I may not say it often enough.
但我从来都是这么想的
But I think it all the time.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我也爱你  宝贝
I love you too, baby.
-你好  -奥利佛  是我
- Hello. - Oliver, it's me.
抱歉  迈克  我现在没时间
Sorry, Mike, I can't talk right now.
我正为一个解决不了的案子忙呢
I'm kinda busy being overwhelmed by a case I can't handle.
看来你没有说服内森
I take it you couldn't convince Nathan
-给你更多人手  -是的
- to get you more people? - No. I couldn't.
这样的话
Well, in that case...
我加入
I'm in.
你给哈维的承诺怎么办
What about your promise to Harvey?
哈维的事我来解决
You let me worry about Harvey.